Leah: Let’s have a look
at Scrum in more detail
Chris: Scrum is an Agile methodology
often called a framework to help
teams to work together on a project.
Scrum is quick and easy to adapt, it
has continuous learning cycles, it
enables fast feedback loops, has clear
visibility and low risk, protects the
team from un-prioritised work requests,
and is focused on delivering value.
Leah: The sprint is a fixed length
event which has a sprint goal.
All events are time-boxed so once
a sprint begins, it is fixed.
The sprint itself, involves a collection
of ‘tasks’ for the team to achieve.
Each task or ‘user story’ is
allocated a level of complexity
called a ‘story point’.
A sprint project board which is also
known as the ‘Sprint Backlog’ is used
to track the tasks, and sub-tasks
are positioned in three columns - ‘To
do’, ‘In progress’, and ‘Done’.
Chris: The Scrum Team [also known
as the Scrum Development Team]
organises and manages its own work.
They deliver the agreed product
increment inside a sprint.
The team consists of different skillsets
and abilities needed to deliver the
product which would likely include
programming, designing, testing,
content writing, and/or business
skills depending on the project.
Leah: Sprint planning is the
first meeting of the sprint.
It is where achievable items or user
stories, are identified from the product
backlog to be moved to the next sprint.
The team would decide in this meeting,
what can be done within the next
sprint, and then refine the user
stories; for example, they would
determine story-points, how tasks
will get done, the definition of
done, dependencies, and sub-tasks.
Chris: The Scrum Master manages the
Scrum Process and remove impediments.
They ensure that the framework is
followed and would predominately
manage the planning meeting taking
into consideration priority, capacity,
and the wider business expectations.
However, before the planning meeting
can take place, the Product Owner
would need to determine the priority
tasks and decide on the sprint goal.
The Product Owner manages the
Product Backlog and optimises
the value of the Product.
Team members also need to allocate their
own tasks on the product ‘backlog’.
Leah: The Daily Scrum, also known as
the ‘Daily Standup’, is a 15-minute
meeting for the internal scrum team,
which is arranged at the same time,
each working day of the sprint.
Its main objective is to determine
progress and update the project board,
also known as the ‘sprint backlog’, and
adapt the ‘product backlog’ if needed.
The focus is on progress and actions, and
self-management is encouraged, as well
as promoting collaboration, improvement,
and transparency amongst team members.
Chris: The Sprint Review is where the
scrum team present their results from the
work they have done in the current sprint,
to the stakeholders and/or the customers.
[The Product Owner would have direct
relationships with the Business
Owner and the Stakeholders.] It
is where feedback is given, and
adaptations, alterations, changes and
or improvements can be planned for.
The sprint review is a working session,
not just a presentation and the
product backlog is adjusted to reflect
new information and or feedback.
It is usually one of the
last events of the sprint.
Leah: The Sprint Retrospective or retro is
the last meeting and concludes the sprint.
This is where the team determine what went
well, what could be improved, what needs
greater understanding, and the actions
that need to be taken, moving forward.
The retro is a safe place where
the team can come together, give
support and productive feedback.
The purpose of the retro is to act on
what has been reviewed, and plan ways
to increase quality and effectiveness.
One of the biggest benefits of
working in Agile is ‘continuous
improvement’, and in Scrum the driver
of improvement is the ‘Retrospective’.